Fei Pan

Research Fellow of CSE, University of Michigan

G google-scholar 🏠 feipan.info 💟 feipan@umich.edu 🖫 7345465633

Research Interest: My passion is to create a general AI system for computer vision tasks that is to proof to be robust, versatile, and unified among all the tasks. My passion is to create a general AI system for computer vision tasks that is to proof to be robust, versatile, and unified among all the tasks. My passion is to create a general AI system for computer vision tasks that is to proof to be robust, versatile, and unified among all the tasks. My passion is to create a general AI system for computer vision tasks that is to proof to be robust, versatile, and unified among all the tasks.

E

EDUCATION	
KAIST Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering Advisor: In So Kweon Thesis: Geometric-guided Domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation	Mar 2018 - Aug 2023
KAIST M.S. in Electrical Engineering Advisor: Chang D. Yoo Thesis: Deep Recursive Segmentation Networks	Mar 2016 - Feb 2018
Xidian University B.S. in Telecommunications Engineering Class Rank: 1/41 GPA: 3.7/4.0	Aug 2011 - Jul 2015
Experience	
University of Michigan Research Fellow Advisor: Stella X. Yu	Sep 2023 - Current
Bosch Robert GmbH Research Internship Advisor: Yu Gao	May 2021 - Nov 2021
Visbody Co., Ltd Internship Advisor: Shaoyi Yang	Aug 2015 - Feb 2016
Scholarship & Awards	
Robert Bosch Ph.D. Scholarship Robert Bosch GmbH Funding Awarded: €44,000 EUR (~ 47,100 USD)	Sept 2019 - Aug 2021
Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship	Dec 2020

Projects

NATURAL HAZARD ENGINEERING

Outstanding Student

Xidian University

Goodix Technology Scholarship

AI/ML for Structure Feature Inference | Research & Software Dev.

Qualcomm Inc. | Funding Awarded: 44,000,000 KWR ($\sim 3,000$ USD)

Goodix Technology Co., Ltd | Funding Awarded: ¥5,000 RMB (~ 700 USD)

Sept 2023 - Current

Sept 2015

Jul 2015

Funded by: National Science Foundation, United States

Goal: Development of AL/ML tools to infer the features of buildings and terrains.

My Work: Experiment with large language models to infer building features, with a proof-of-concept study on classification and segmentation.

Intelligent Transportation Systems

Robust Vehicle Detection from Multi-camera Views | Research Internship

May 2021 - Nov 2021

Funded by: Robert Bosch GmbH

Goal: New algorithms for domain adaptation in various utilization environments with fusion of multiple visual data. My Work: Developing a new framework of domain adaptation for multiple perception tasks in driving scenes, with a specific focus on vehicle detection from multiple views from CCTV cameras in road scenes, considering the domain gaps among multiple cameras and diverse weather conditions

Shared Sensing for Cooperative Cars | Project Member

May 2021 - Nov 2021

Funded by: Robert Bosch GmbH

Goal: Developing new technologies toward the collaboration between a swarm of vehicles and CCTV cameras.

My Work: Conducting static background using background subtraction algorithms; to build a CNN-based segmentation model for road mark detection.

Autonomous Driving

Driver Assistant Active Safety | Project Member

Apr 2016 - Feb 2017

Funded by: National Core Research Center of South Korea

Goal: Build a learning-based high-performance vision algorithm for active safety driver assistance.

My Work: Participating in creating drowsiness labeling dataset, and building a CNN-based algorithm for detecting the drowsiness status of the drivers.

Publications

Conference Proceedings

[1] Zero-shot Building Attribute Extraction from Large-Scale Vision and Language Models.

Fei Pan, Sangryul Jeon, Brian Wang, Frank Mckenna, Stella Yu.

IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2024

[2] ML-BPM: Multi-teacher Learning with Bidirectional Photometric Mixing for Open Compound Domain Adaptation in Semantic Segmentation.

Fei Pan, Sungsu Heo, Seokju Lee, In So Kweon.

European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022.

Paper | Poster

[3] Attentive and Contrastive Learning for Joint Depth and Motion Field Estimation.

Seokju Lee, Francois Rameau, Fei Pan, In So Kweon.

IEEE / CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021

Paper | Code

[4] Two-phase Pseudo Label Densification for Self-training based Domain Adaptation.

Inkyu Shin, Sanghyun Woo, Fei Pan, In So Kweon.

European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020.

[5] Unsupervised Intra-domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation through Self-Supervision.

Fei Pan, Inkyu Shin, Francois Rameau, Seokju Lee, In So Kweon.

IEEE / CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2020.

Paper | Code | Project Page

[6] Variational Prototyping-Encoder: One-Shot Learning with Prototypical Images.

Junsik Kim, Tae-Hyun Oh, Seokju Lee, Fei Pan, In So Kweon.

IEEE / CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019.

Paper | Code

[7] Driver Drowsiness Detection System Based on Feature Representation Learning Using Various Deep Networks. Sanghyuk Park, Fei Pan, Sunghun Kang, and Chang D. Yoo.

Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV) Workshop on Driver Drowsiness Detection from Video, 2016. Paper

JOURNAL ARTICLES

[1] CCTV-Calib: a Toolbox to Calibrate Surveillance Cameras Around the Globe.

Francois Rameau, Jaesung Choe, Fei Pan, Seokju Lee, and In So Kweon.

Machine Vision and Applications, 2024

Paper | Code

PREPRINT & WORKING PAPERS

[1] ImageNet-D: Benchmarking Neural Network Robustness on Diffusion Synthetic Object Chengshuang Zhang, Fei Pan, Junmo Kim, In So Kweon, Chengzhi Mao.

IEEE / CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2024 (Under Review)

[2] OpenSlot: Real-World Open Set Recognition with Object Centric Learning.

Xu Yin, Fei Pan, Yuchi Huo, Zixuan Xie, Sungeui Yoon.

IEEE / CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2024 (Under Review)

[3] Fine-grained Background Representation for Weakly Supervised Semantic Segmentation.

Xu Yin, Woobin Im, Dongbo Min, Yuchi Huo, Fei Pan, Sungeui Yoon.

Under Review, 2024

[4] Leveraging Motion Priors from Videos for Advancing Unsupervised Domain Adaptation in Semantic Segmen-

Fei Pan*, Xu Yin*, Seokju Lee, Sungeui Yoon, In So Kweon.

Under Review. 2024

[5] Masking-augmented Collaborative Domain Congregation for Multi-target Domain Adaptation in Semantic Segmentation.

Fei Pan*, Dong He*, Xu Yin, Chengshuang Zhang, Munchurl Kim.

35th IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IV), 2024 (Under Review)

[6] Labeling Where Adapting Fails: Cross-Domain Semantic Segmentation with Point Supervision via Active Selection.

Fei Pan, Framcois Rameau, Junsik Kim, In So Kweon. arXiv:2206.00181, 2022

Academic Reviews

Conference Review

IEEE / CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2024

IEEE / CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2023

IEEE / CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023

IEEE / CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2022

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) Workshop: Self-Supervised Learning Theory and Practice, 2021

The International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) Workshop: Self-Supervised Learning for Reasoning and Perception, 2021

Journal Review

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI), 2023

Image and Vision Computing, 2023

Neurocomputing, 2023

Computer Vision and Image Understanding, 2023

Pattern Recognition Letters, 2022

Neurocomputing, 2022

ACADEMIC SERVICES

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Advanced Topics in Deep Learning for Robotics and Vision: Domain Adaptation

Teaching Assistant, 2021

Deep Learning for Computer Vision: Generative Adversarial Learning

 $Teaching\ Assistant,\ 2020$

Talks & Keynote Speakings

Zero-shot Building Attribute Extraction from Large-Scale Vision and Language Models.

NHERI Computational Symposium, UCLA Luskin Conference Center, Feb 1 2024

Unsupervised Intra-domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation through Self-Supervision.

Oral Presentation at CVPR, Jun 16 2020 (Remote)

Driver Drowsiness Detection System Based on Feature Representation Learning Using Various Deep Networks. The ACCV Workshop on Driver Drowsiness Detection from Video, Taipei, Nov 24 2016

STUDENT MENTORING

Brian Wang, Master Student at CSE, University of Michigan